I think it's important that you're always trying to, you know, change and grow and become
Yeah, for me, I like to order different stuff. I always go for the
For the dish that I haven't tried before
So I don't like exactly yeah, even for wine like even I know I like this wine a lot
I always want to try a different bottle and would you say
This is abnormal in China or maybe you're influenced from America or
is this just your personality in general?
I don't know.
Maybe it's the 88 kids, you know?
Maybe.
AD, what about you?
Do you like to try new stuff?
I always like to try new stuff.
He's spent a lot of time traveling as well.
For example, last night my favorite dish was the asparagus because it was new.
Really?
Yeah.
What about your friends?
Everyone likes to try new stuff.
They don't like to taste the same food over and over again.
So the one signature dish or several signature dishes that never…
The signature dish is a different story.
If it's really good, and it's really associated with the restaurant,
they would want to taste it when they're here.
But would they go back to taste it again?
Yeah. But not with the exact same menu as before.
One signature dish and different combinations.
So maybe that's our way of doing pairing.
Maybe that's also our way of why we like control.
Because for people who are very aesthetic in ordering Chinese food, the ordering is
part of the creation. The way, how you order different dishes, how you choose to combine them, and also the sequence
of presenting the food is very essential to the whole experience.
And someone who knows how to order would have a very different effect.
In our restaurant, we also choose for them.
For example, we make sure when they come next time,
they don't have the exact same menu as last time.
But we just choose for them.
Yeah, but I think, and this is what kind of AdWord
enlightened me to the local preferences,
is that we can change some, and you can choose some dishes
for them, but they also need to have some choice.
That's why we have these supplements now.
I offer the signature dish as an option, but I never put it on the main menu.
What's the signature dish?
The chicken. It's not mine.
Oh, yeah, the hot chicken.
Sourdough.
Yeah, so if guests come and they love the signature dish,
or they want to show it to a friend or something,
they can order it.
But the menu doesn't have that anymore.
Because I was getting sick of cooking the same thing.
I wanted to keep trying new stuff.
Yeah, I think it's actually a good balance.
It's not on the menu.
It's actually a good balance. It's not on the menu, it's still available. So only people who, you know, people would even, the people who order this dish for the
privileged experience would even feel more, even more privileged.
Right, right. Exactly.
In the know.
Yeah.
There was one question prepared before, and I think it's time to ask that question. Because you are a foreigner coming to China to do Chinese food.
I don't say Chinese food.
Am I doing Chinese food?
You always said last night you were doing Cantonese food.
No, no, that's from the article.
The article says you are more than Cantonese and you agreed to the term because you didn't
like the word fusion. I didn't create that word.
Some guests that come in say,
oh, you're kind of like a modern Cantonese restaurant.
And when guests tell me that,
I like it. I like it much more than,
oh, I like your fusion concepts.
Yeah, me too.
I think it's kind of cool because it's...
Only that I don't view it as modern Cantonese, I view it as modern Chinese.
Yeah.
And the reason I say that is because you use Chinese ingredients, you use Chinese seasoning,
maybe not the traditional Chinese seasoning, but you know, the ingredients are from here, of course.
Yeah, it is Chinese food technically, you know.
Chinese food, maybe not Chinese cooking.
Yeah, cuisine.
Cuisine, yeah.
I mean, even that's in the evolution.
Before, I think we were a little bit more closer
to the palate of Cantonese.
But because Shenzhen has so many different people
from all over China,
it was such a... I would get a complaint that it's not spicy enough,
or we didn't use enough bread, or we didn't do this, or you know.
And so I had to kind of open the experience to more than just, you know, Cantonese.
So I'm from Yantai.
Okay.
Same place as the Wagyu beef is from. The Wagyu dish is also from Yantai, the same place as the Wagyu beef is from.
The Wagyu dish is also from Yantai.
Our style is Lu Cai.
And there are actually two styles of Lu Cai, which means Shannonese food.
One is the western, more inland, a lot of sauce and soy sauce.
Yeah.
In the western part, in the eastern part,
it's a lot of seafood.
The fish I had yesterday reminds me of that kind of stuff, cooking.
Okay.
Yeah, stock, seafood, and lighter seasoning.
Right, right.
And never overcook.
So we also cook our shrimp,
and the shrimp, the temperature has to be perfect
and not overcooked.
So I feel in the core of fandangy
and the core of the traditional Chinese cooking,
I'm much aligned.
I agree with you.
But you didn't go to find wisdom or inspiration
from the Chinese style of cooking, no?
Sometimes.
How curious are you in the Chinese cooking,
all the Chinese cooking styles?
I mean, I would love to actually spend time
in a Chinese kitchen.
But it's just kind of hard right now.
Then priority wise, learning ingredients and learning cooking styles?
I mean they're the same. Because usually when I find an ingredient, I research how it's
cooked locally first. And then I maybe take some ideas or maybe do something completely
different. But I'll always try to do it how the local might prepare the ingredient first.
Is it hard to learn or is it very different, the cooking techniques?
I mean to learn, to make it good is easy, to make it great is difficult. So I think
to be a master you need many years of experience and lots of understanding.
But I think if you just spend time in a kitchen, you already have a certain understanding of
how food, proteins, liquids, fats all react to different heat, temperatures, fermentation,
acids, all of these things kind of interact.
So if you know the foundations of cooking, you can kind of jump in any cooking style
and I think somewhat achieve good results.
But in Chinese cuisine, and I think the Chinese, you know, you make, you pick certain details
that are very, you know, like the Cantonese, the way they steam
a fish.
Even if I steamed it perfectly, it still wouldn't be good enough, you know, because they wouldn't
master it to perfection.
Yeah, you know, you need to have some sort of street credit, you know, you need to be...
Street credit, but also the way it's presented.
Like the Cantonese require it to be right in front of you, you have ten seconds, and after the ten seconds it's going back. By the way, it's done here.
You cannot do that.
Yeah, exactly. So I can't approach it the same way. I have to do it differently. And
we tried to do some ingredients closer to traditional methods, and that was always the
biggest rejection in the
dining room. That's true. And so it's like okay you know let's all cook the way I
know how to cook best maybe with a little bit of influence or I can improve
my skills by understanding another type of skill you I think some hints of the traditional way of cooking can be pleasant in the experience,
but too much of it, then you draw yourself into this comparison that you don't want to.
Yeah, exactly.
And then you become fusion, bad fusion.
One big difference I noticed between Chinese cooking and Western cooking is in the sauce.
Most Chinese sauce is fermented, and most Western sauce is never fermented.
But we've been doing, or I've been doing fermented sauce very early, even in any country I worked
in. I think it's a big inspiration from Asian countries.
Western sauces now, I think, have a lot of fermentation involved in them.
Classically, Western sauces don't season, instead of salt, we use, you know, garum or soy sauces,
Jiangyus, however you want to call it, made from the ingredient.
So, instead of, you know, fermenting soybeans and rice, we ferment beef and rice.
You know, and that's, and then we season our beef shu with that.
And then instead of adding acid, vinegar,
which is also a type of fermentation, we might use another type of lacto-fermentation. So
we're just taking the same kind of core way of approaching a Western sauce, but we're
adding more flavor and more levels of flavor by using fermentation
subtly.
How do you like the, last question then.
Okay.
Yeah.
So how do you like the work experience here?
Like I know since you've been here, it's mostly COVID, right?
The pandemic.
Yeah, I guess.
I didn't even realize.
Yeah, I mean, it's good. I miss home a little bit.
But in terms of the work environments, it's well balanced.
We don't do lunch here, which is, you know, I can come in to work.
I only work 12 hours, which is pretty good for a restaurant.
You mentioned 16 hours.
Yeah, when I first started some of the jobs, I worked 16 hours.
It depends. Like when I worked on the farm, your work and your life is very much mixed, right?
Because you wake up early to feed the animals.
But you know, you might spend a couple hours outside in the garden,
and then go into the kitchen to prepare the ingredients
and you eat with the whole family.
So your whole life is kind of about this whole cycle.
Here it's, you know, I don't have that privilege, but it's, you know,
I try to keep a positive work environment, you know, a lot of chefs are,
I get angry sometimes, but most of the time, you know, it's about, you know, we play music in the
kitchen, we try to have fun and laugh and cook good food for each other.
The customers, you start to figure out the customers?
Yeah, and then I started to figure out the clients.
And you know, also our return guests, like Edward's saying,
we have quite a lot of information on them,
so we can give them dishes that we know what they'll like.
Obviously, I'd like to do more than we are,
but it's always balancing what we can handle with the team.
And then, yeah, the training the staff is also exciting too, and teaching them different
ways.
And now, after three years, we've had quite a few people come through the kitchen and
move on and continue their success.
So that's the most rewarding to be honest actually.
Is seeing the stories of these young generation of Chinese cooks.
Planting seeds.
Yeah, exactly.
That's a good metaphor.
Planting seeds for the future growth.
And I'm curious to see because I think China has such a strong history, you know, more
than almost any other country.
And through that history, there's a lot of rules and traditions about cuisine and regions. And a lot of people, like you said, you know, this is how we do it in our region,
and this is what we care about. And it's good to have that. And it's good to have that history.
But it sometimes scares people from breaking away from those traditions, from being innovative.
And I see chefs in China, if they choose to work at a restaurant like An Su,
they're already making that choice to break away tradition and to see what else.
And I've got two chefs that have worked two years for me and now are running
their own kitchens. And I'm curious to see if I taught them. Because it's like how they
approach innovation and creating a new dish is very foreign for them. And that creativity,
and once you spark that, it's exciting to see.
And since they have more knowledge about this tradition, I always feel like you need to respect it.
There are going to be better chefs than me because of that.
Different chefs.
Be aware of the tradition, know the context, but don't limit to have the freedom to break them or innovate.
Right.
Me too.
Last night after the dinner, I thanked Edward for bringing into two changes, this whole experience and the possibilities.
It's very exciting.
Thank you.
Thank you for the interview.
Thanks, guys.
Thank you.
Mysterious AD.
All right.
Bye.